





Consultant - Project Management and Technology seeking roles in Delivery Management, Project Management, and Data Architecture



Current Location: Kolkata Total Experience: 28 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Pune Highest Degree: MCA[Computers]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance Role: Program Mgr

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Project Management, PMO, Enterprise Architecture, Customer Service, Program Management, Data

Architecture, Delivery Management, Application Support, Scrum Master, Agile, SDLC Life Cycle

Verified : L Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Work Authorization

## Summary

Arijit is an experienced Program & Project delivery manager with 27 years of IT industry experience, working with customers across US, Europe, Asia and Africa, in onsite client-facing roles and offshore delivery. With a significant number of engagements in Banking, Payments and Retail domains, he has helped build and implement enterprise transformation and digital transformation solutions.

He is an Enterprise Architect designing and implementing information solutions for customers on OLTP, OLAP and Client Server platforms. A certified PMP, Scrum Master and SAFE professional, he has worked on multiple engagements with Agile and SDLC methodologies.

Arijit has handled large portfolios of 150+ people in 20+ projects, handling account planning, budgeting, resourcing, project delivery, operations and P&L, helping customers achieve their annual IT cost and schedule targets.

# **Work Experience**

PRM Fincon Services Private Limited as Consultant - Project Management and Technology Jun 2020 to Oct 2020

Synopsis: Advisory to company management on project management and industry best practices on process and technical aspects for a FinTech product being developed for digitization Role: Consultant on Contract:

Client Management - 3600

Business Development - business discussions with prospects, case studies, SoW

Process establishment for the following - Hardware configuration selection, Hardware performance baselining, Agile Development (Jira, Bitbucket), Deployment & Release, Project Management, Production Support

Cognizant Technology Solutions Pvt. Ltd. as Offshore Delivery Lead Mar 2003 to Sep 2019

Program & Project Management - Representative Assignments

Project: Offshore Delivery Lead - Portfolio of a Swiss Bank, India

Synopsis: Core Banking, Client management and reporting applications to support Swiss operations of the Private Bank. Development, support and enhancements of these applications using J2EE, Mcrosoft Azure Cloud, Al/ML, Big

Data technologies, .Net, Oracle and other legacy technology Role: Offshore Delivery Center Leader

Management & Technical Leadership to Offshore team

Client reporting, metrics reporting

Directing technology R&D, Architecture and Design reviews

Projects monitoring and health review - cost, schedule, utilization, profitability

Account planning and Business forecasting

Facilitating Audits, Trainings, and Delivery Excellence practices

Facilitating resourcing & recruitment and team building activities

Business Development, proposal building & presentations, estimates and pricing reviews, Contract negotiations

2019 Revenue of 22mn USD from 20+ projects with high profitability. 150+ offshore project team Multiple client appreciation mails on deployments - 4 regular release cycles + 4 fast path releases / year

New business worth 2.5mn USD from 10 proposal wins in 2019

## **Important**

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Project: Pilot for Digitalization of Results Management for EBRD, London, UK

Synopsis: Client was looking for Digitalization of EBRD Results management as a first step to turning Digital Cognizant provided solution using Cloud and Big Data technologies AWS, Hadoop, Sqoop, HIVE, Tableau, Backbase,

Role: Scrum Master & Data / Reporting Lead - 8 sprints over 4 months

Conduct Scrum events - Sprint Planning & Estimations, Stand-ups, Backlog grooming, Reviews, Retrospectives Facilitate meetings with Product SMEs, resources for team (access, documentation, data)

Requirements, Data design, Data management, Clarifications with product SMEs

Created Report specs, demonstrated user console with 7 management dashboards / multiple views Impact: First Digital program of EBRD, setting the stage for larger initiatives

Project: Offshore Project Manager for portfolio of Global / Swiss Private Bank, India, Switzerland Synopsis: The Bank uses OLYMPIC to maintain the entire Back Office accounting. The Customer Service Specialists, Bankers and Traders use the Front Office Suite of Applications (Web-based) to provide advisory, and investments and trading in the areas of Fixed Income, Equities, Mutual Funds, Hedge Funds and other instruments. Build, enhancement and support of applications on Java, .Net, Sybase, Business Objects applications for customer Role: Offshore Project Manager

Risk tracking and mitigation, Metrics establishment and Reporting

Planning and coordinating Delivery efforts

Scope, Cost and Schedule Management

Resource allocation, training and deployment

Quality compliance, technical reviews, proposal building, estimations and contracts preparations

Data Modelling, Data Architecture Lead

Impact: 10+ projects, 70+ member team with 5% Y-o-Y cost savings for client, Annual Billing ~ USD 9mn

EDW for US Asset Management company owned by major Australian bank, India

Synopsis: A US based Asset Management arm of a major Australian Bank was looking to design an EDW to facilitate Data Integration from multiple sources and subsequent management Reporting. Data is drawn from multiple sources, internal MDM systems, internal Investment applications, and industry market data, LIPPER and Morningstar. Project encompass

### CGI Inc, USA as Senior Consultant

Feb 1997 to Dec 2002

Built Sales Pipeline Application for reporting to CGI Corporate group - Developer / Data Designer Support of Merchandising application for Blockbuster Entertainment Group - Developer / Designer Support of Replenishment system for Blockbuster Entertainment Group - Developer / Designer Multiple Year 2000 projects for Blockbuster Entertainment Group - Y2K Tester Support of internal systems at CGI - Developer / Data Designer

#### TCS as System Analyst Aug 1994 to Feb 1997

Role: Onsite Requirements Analyst Offshore Designer / Module Lead Database design Program Design Oversee development

Responsible for modules in 2 systems developed for TCS:

Hire Purchase system for retail customer, CJ&Co, Mauritius - Onsite Requirement Analyst and Team Lead Mne Management System at Piparwar Coal Mne (CCL) for WAL Australia - Team Lead / Designer / Developer

#### Digital Equipment (I) Pvt Ltd as Software Engineer Aug 1992 to Jul 1994

Faculty Member for Digital Education Services imparting technical training to clients like TISCO, TVS, TRF, SAIL, Coal India Limited, Birla Technical Services, Organon, BARC etc.

^ Back to Top

## **Education**

UG: B.Com (Commerce) from St Xaviers College, Kolkata in 1985

PG: MCA (Computers) from Harcourt Butler technology institute, Kanpur in 1992

^ Back to Top

# **IT Skills**

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
Windows, Unix, Sun Solaris		
DEC VAX / OpenVMS		
VB6, C, PRO*C, SQL, Cold Fusion		
uniFace, Forte, Oracle*Forms		
Oracle, SQL Server, Sybase, SSIS		
Oracle Data Modeler		
Sybase Power Designer, ERWin, Visio, TOAD		
Crystal Reports, SSRS, Oracle*Reports		

^ Back to Top

\_....

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Bengali	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Expert	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

# **Affirmative Action**

## **Work Authorization**

Category: General

Countries: India

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Temporary/Contractual Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved @ 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.